<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solid-mechanics on Artur L Gower</title>
    <link>https://arturgower.github.io/tags/solid-mechanics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solid-mechanics on Artur L Gower</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Artur L Gower</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:28:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arturgower.github.io/tags/solid-mechanics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Surface waves and instabilities</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/surface-solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/surface-solid/</guid>
      <description>a surface wave or wrinkle.   -- Summary Most biological materials (and industrial) are reinforced with stiff fibres or are under tension. I figure out how these mechanisms influence elastic surface waves and the formation of surface wrinkles. The main reasons to do this are
 will give us greater control over surface waves or forming textured surfaces (using surface wrinkles). use these surface waves and surface wrinkles to measure biological materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Elastodynamics with Radial Symmetry (Elasticidade nao linear com simetria radial)</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/publication/radial-elasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 13:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/publication/radial-elasticity/</guid>
      <description>Summary The image above shows the story of a wave propagating in a sphere, like a planet, travelling through both time t and space R (distance from origin).
The wave is an elastic wave with radial symmetry, so we can imagine this as a wave created from the centre of the earth. The colour indicates the amplitude of the wave, with yellow-ish corresponding to no wave. In this image the wave begins at 1km from the centre of the earth, R=1, at time t=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mechanics of soft solids</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/initial-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/initial-stress/</guid>
      <description>Most of my work on elastic solids has been on constitutive equations, that is, mathematically describing the different components of a solid, and how these effect the forces and deformations. With the two main themes being stressed solids and fibre-reinforced solids. I have also explored how to use waves and instabilities to characterise solids.
Initially stressed solids The driving question is how to mathematically describe the mechanical response of residually stressed solids?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>