<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Artur L Gower</title>
    <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Artur L Gower</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Artur L Gower</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 10:01:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arturgower.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave Software</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/wave-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 10:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/wave-software/</guid>
      <description>I write software to efficiently calculate wave scattering between particles, and to calculate effective waves from homogenisation methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surface waves and instabilities</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/surface-solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/surface-solid/</guid>
      <description>a surface wave or wrinkle.   -- Summary Most biological materials (and industrial) are reinforced with stiff fibres or are under tension. I figure out how these mechanisms influence elastic surface waves and the formation of surface wrinkles. The main reasons to do this are
 will give us greater control over surface waves or forming textured surfaces (using surface wrinkles). use these surface waves and surface wrinkles to measure biological materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entropy GO</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/entropy_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 21:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/entropy_go/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Scattering</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/multiple-scattering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/multiple-scattering/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on multiply scattering in random media. See example video below! I develop methods to calculate the ensemble average of the wave, which I compare with numerical benchmarks based on the multipole method.
  Back-scattering from a random arrangement of particles.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industrial Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/industry/</guid>
      <description>img { float: right; }  -- Examples The projects below come from commercial and industrial challenges.
  Tracking train tracks How to track a train using only a camera? We designed a method that extracts the curvature of the tracks and removes errors caused by the train jiggling.    The blue is captured from a camera on-board a train. To eliminate the shaking, we formulated an optimization method that recovers the real position of the tracks, in red.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mechanics of soft solids</title>
      <link>https://arturgower.github.io/project/initial-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturgower.github.io/project/initial-stress/</guid>
      <description>Most of my work on elastic solids has been on constitutive equations, that is, mathematically describing the different components of a solid, and how these effect the forces and deformations. With the two main themes being stressed solids and fibre-reinforced solids. I have also explored how to use waves and instabilities to characterise solids.
Initially stressed solids The driving question is how to mathematically describe the mechanical response of residually stressed solids?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>